SARA **NOLAN**

109 Malibu Drive, Eatontown, NJ 🏚 732-737-1820

saraa.ann28@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sara-n-940845161 in





OBJECTIVE

Experienced Practice Manager with a degree in business administration and 4.5 years of experience working within the veterinary industry and a demonstrated history of over 10 years working with animals and pet owners. Seeking employment within the pet care/veterinary industry.



SKILLS

- Coordinating and leading effective teams; strong interpersonal skills
- Ability to make decisions guickly and independently
- Strong organizational skills and attention to detail
- Ability to handle fast-paced/stressful situations in a calm professional manner

- Identifying problems; conflict resolution and management
- Ability to communicate effectively; ability to analyze and interpret data; ability to plan, develop and coordinate multiple projects
- Clinical experience



EXPERIENCE

Practice Manager | Banfield Pet Hospital

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

- ✓ In partnership with the Chief of Staff, managed day-to-day operations ensuring the team provides the highest quality of veterinary care.
- ✓ Responsible to oversee staff recruitment, training, supervision and appraisals; addressed employee issues with confidentiality; directed the cross-training of personnel to effectively utilize employees as well as to build skill levels
- ✓ Optimized technology, standardized processes and procedures, identified and resolved workflow issues
- ✓ Oversees inventory and purchases of medical and office supplies
- ✓ Provide monthly reporting with recommendations or action plans on any issues; interpret financial reports/data to effectively manage the office.

Shift Lead | Banfield Pet Hospital

MAY 2015 - MAY 2019

- ✓ Helped provide day-to-day supervision of the team when called upon and responsible for ensuring quality. medical care, exceptional client service, associate engagement and maximum productivity.
- ✓ Helped foster an environment where a team can deliver quality, efficient and effective veterinary care while promoting an environment that engages associates.

- ✓ Providing professional, efficient and exceptional client service ensuring all associates do the same, to include client education about preventive care, pet health needs, hospital services, marketing campaigns, and other related information.
- ✓ Assisting in effectively scheduling associates to meet client needs according, while proactively planning time off.
- ✓ Ensured compliance of all practice policies and procedures in accordance with company protocols.

Petcare Lead & Dog Trainer | Petsmart

JUNE 2011 - MAY 2015

Dog Trainer/Petcare Team Leader

- ✓ Ensured compliance of all company policies and procedures as well as the safety and security of
- ✓ company assets, customers, pets, and associates.
- ✓ Provided exceptional customer service by genuinely and effectively engaging with customers
- ✓ Monitored safety and wellbeing of every pet and associate in the store
- ✓ Helped maintain and enforce an environment where pet health and care are first and foremost.



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Business Administration and Management | Rutgers University 2018 – CURRENT

Associate of Arts - AA, Business Administration and Management | Brookdale Community College

2015 - 2018



ACTIVITIES

Volunteer Experience:

- Under My Wing Avian Refuge
 - o Animal Keeper
 - o Cause: Animal Welfare
 - o Dates volunteered 2008 2009
 - o Assisted with daily bird maintenance and feeding.
- Clean Ocean Action
 - o Cause: Environment
 - o Dates volunteered 2018-present
 - o Volunteered with local beach clean-up efforts.